<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="44"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[A good man never dies–




                              In worthy deed and prayer


                             And helpful hands, and honest eyes,


                              If smiles or tears be there:


                             Who lives for you and me–




                              Lives for the world he tries


                             To help–he lives eternally.


                              A good man never dies.








                             Who lives to bravely take


                              His share of toil and stress,


                             And, for his weaker fellows’ sake,


                              Makes every burden less,–



                             He may, at last, seem worn–



                              Lie fallen–hands and eyes


                             Folded–yet, though we mourn and mourn,


                              A good man never dies.







                             (James Whitcomb Riley)]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[“      Our dead are never dead









                           to us, until we have



                                   forgotten them.







                                                          - George Eliot





































                                               R.I.P]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[content









                                4               Photo of the late








                                                R.S Owusu




                                5               Order of Services and








                                                Officiating Clergy



                                6               Biography                                                          You will be














                             10                 Photo Gallery




























                                                                                   12  Sep, 1943
                                                                                      th
                                                                                                     Birth]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[18                     Legacy                             content














                                   20                        Tributes













                                     35                      Hymns and








                                                             Readings




                                     37                      Obituary









     Remembered

















          29 , March, 2021
               th
                                   Death]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Mr. R.S Owusu









                                                                      A.K.A




                                                            Buama












                                                                                                      4]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[ORDER OF




               SERVICE                                  .          OFFICIATING

                                                                   CLERGY                                    .





               PART I


                 1.      Procession of Choirs and Clergy            1.       Rev. D.K Tetteh - Synod
                 2.      Call to Worship                                     Moderator, EPCG Western
                 3.      Opening Hymn: 589: 1-3                              Presbytery
                 4.      Prayer and Creed
                 5.      Brief Word of Welcome                      2.       Rev. Mrs. C.A Tutu - District
                 6.      Biography of the late Mr. Owusu                     Pastor,EPCG Lartebiokorshie
                 7.      Tributes                                            District, Accra
                 8.      Praises and thanks oﬀering
                 9.      hymn: 337: 1-2                             3.       Rev. N.J.S Tam - District
                 10.     Scripture Reading                                   Pastor, EPCG, Have-Etoe
                 11.     Sermon
                 12.     Oﬀertory                                   4.       Rev. W.K Abbot-Attah -
                 13.     Presentation of wreaths                             District Pastor, EPCG Have
                 14.     Dedication of oﬀerings                              Gboxome (Sub-District)
                 15.     Announcements/Recognitions
                 16.     Vote of Thanks                             5.       Rev. F.S.K Ayeeson - District
                 17.     hymn: 318: 1-2, 4                                   Pastor, EPCG, New Achimota
                 18.     Final commendations and rites                       District, Accra
                 19.     Closing prayer and benediction
                 20.     Recessional hymn: 651: 1-3                 6.       Rev. Jean-Paul Agidi - EPCG,
                                                                             Menpasem District, Accra.

               PART II                                              7.       Rev. B.A Anipa - 2nd Minis

                                                                             ter, EPCG, Lartebiokorshie
                 1.      Invocation                                          District, Accra
                 2.      Hymn: 298: 1-2
                 3.      Internment                                 8.       Catechist Mrs. Millicent Doe -
                 4.      The Lord’s Prayer and Benediction                   EPCG, New Abossey Okai,
                 5.      Closing Hymn: 591: 1-3                              Accra

                                                                    9.       Rtd. Catechist Mrs. Bernice
                                                                             Doe, EPCG, New Abossey
                                                                             Okai, Accra

                                                                    10.      Catechist H.K Foli - EPCG,
                                                                             Have-Etoe.
                          Funeral and Burial Service .                                                5]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[BIOGRAPHY






                                                                                  OF THE LATE


                             ROBINSON STEPHEN KODZO OWUSU

                                                                              (A.K.A BUAMA)
                                                                                                    6]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Biography .








            Early Life.




                        TEACH US TO NUMBER OUR DAYS THAT WE MAY GAIN A HEART OF
                        WISDOM – PS 90:12





                    ROBINSON STEPHEN KODZO OWUSU (AKA BUAMA) WAS BORN

                    ON SEPT 12, 1943 IN THE “HOLY” VILLAGE OF HAVE-ETOE IN

                    THE VOLTA REGION. HIS  PARENTS  WERE EMMANUEL KOFI
                    OWUSU KAKRABA  AND ELIZABETH ADZO ASEMBRI  ALL  OF

                    BLESSED MEMORY. HE WAS THE SECOND CHILD OF THE MOTHER’S

                    SEVEN  CHILDREN  AND  THE  FOURTH  OF  THE  FATHER’S  FIFTEEN

                    CHILDREN. HE  WAS,  BAPTIZED  AND  CONFIRMED  INTO  THE E.P.
                    CHURCH, GHANA. ALL OF THESE TOOK PLACE AT HAVE-ETOE.








































                  Mr. R.S Owusu .                             7]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Biography .








            Education.


                  HE  ATTENDED  THE E.P. SCHOOLS  FROM PRIMARY  TO MIDDLE SCHOOL  FORM
                  FOUR AT HAVE-ETOE. AFTER MIDDLE SCHOOL FORM, FOUR HE CONTINUED TO A

                  COMMERCIAL SCHOOL  IN KOFORIDUA. LATER  WHILE  WORKING,  HE  TOOK DIS-
                  TANCE LEARNING COURSES  IN  THE A.I.A. (ASSOCIATION  OF INTERNATIONAL
                  ACCOUNTANTS), LONDON IN ACCRA.



            Career.


                  AFTER COMPLETION OF THE COMMERCIAL SCHOOL AT KOFORIDUA YOUNG R.S
                  MOVED  TO KEJEBI  TO  TAKE  A  JOB  AT KEJEBI ASATU SECONDARY SCHOOL  AS
                  STOREKEEPER. THAT WAS IN THE YEAR 1963. LATE 1964, HE MOVED TO ACCRA

                  AND WORKED WITH A LAW FIRM AS A SECRETARY IN ADABRAKA. NOT TOO LONG
                  AFTER HE JOINED, A FRENCH SHIPPING COMPANY, SCANSHIP (GHANA LTD) AND
                  THEIR SISTER COMPANY ALLRAINE AS AN ACCOUNTS CLERK. BY DINT OF HARD
                  WORK, LOYALTY AND DEDICATION HE WAS, PROMOTED TO THE POSITION OF AN
                  ACCOUNTANT AND LATER AS THE SENIOR ACCOUNTANT. HE WAS THE SECOND IN
                  CHARGE AT THE ACCOUNTS DEPARTMENT.


                  R.S WORKED IN SCANSHIP AND ALLRAINE FOR THE REST OF HIS WORKING LIFE
                  UNTIL HE ATTAINED THE AGE 69. WHEN THE COMPANY MOVED ITS OFFICES FROM
                  ACCRA TO THE TEMA PORT, R.S MOVED AS WELL, COMMUTING BETWEEN ACCRA
                  AND TEMA  DAILY.  HE  FINALLY  RETIRED  IN 2014  AFTER  SEVERAL  CONTRACT

                  RENEWALS  BY  HIS  EMPLOYERS  IN  RECOGNITION  OF  HIS  LOYALTY,  DEDICATION,
                  ASTOUNDING  SKILLS  AND  DEPTH  OF  KNOWLEDGE  IN  HIS  POSITION  AS SENIOR
                  ACCOUNTANT FOR SEVERAL YEARS IN THE COMPANY.



            Family Life.




                  COMING FROM A LARGE FAMILY, HE WAS PREPARED TO BE ACCOMMODATING AND
                  SOCIABLE. HE OPENED HIS HOME TO EVERYONE, WHETHER FAMILY OR NOT. HE
                  EMBRACED  THE  WHOLE  FAMILY,  NIECES,  AND  NEPHEWS  AND  BEYOND. HE  WAS
                  ALSO THERE FOR HAVE CITIZENS LIVING IN AND AROUND AWOSHIE, KWASHIEMAN
                  AND GBAWE. THERE WAS ENOUGH TO EAT AND DRINK ANYTIME ONE PAID A VISIT,
                  OR  WAS,  INVITED  BY  HIM. HIS  LIFE  WAS  INCOMPLETE  WITHOUT  COMPANY. HE
                  SPENT MOST OF HIS RETIREMENT ENJOYING THE COMPANY OF HIS IMMEDIATE AND
                  EXTENDED FAMILY AND FRIENDS.


                   8                                                              Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Biography .








            Marital Life.




                  HE FOUND HIS FIRST LOVE, MARGARET AMU, IN 1963 WHEN HE WORKED BRIEFLY
                  AT  THE KEJEBI ASATU SECONDARY SCHOOL. THEIR  RELATIONSHIP  BLOSSOMED
                  INTO MARRIAGE AND THEY WERE BLESSED WITH THREE CHILDREN; MATILDA, DORIS
                  AND MAWULI.



                  HOWEVER, THE FIRST MARRIAGE WAS, DISSOLVED AFTER IT SUFFERED SOME IRREPA-
                  RABLE TURBULENCE MANY YEARS AFTER. R.S, NOT WANTING TO LIVE A LONELY
                  LIFE, REMARRIED TO GRACE, WHO HE LATER WEDDED.



            Religious Life.




                  HE  WAS  A  STRONG  MEMBER  OF  THE EVANGELICAL PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH,
                  GHANA  (EPCG)  AND  WORSHIPPED  AT  THE  NEW  ABBOSEY  OKINE  CHURCH
                  (NEW ABOSS)  WITH  THE  WIFE GRACE. IT  WAS  IN  THE CHURCH  THEY  WERE
                  WEDDED. HE WAS A MEMBER OF THE CHURCH FINANCE COMMITTEE, A MEN’S
                  FELLOWSHIP  EXECUTIVE  MEMBER  AND  A  CONSECRATED  PRESBYTER  OF  THE

                  CHURCH.
                  R.S AND GRACE TOOK VERY GOOD CARE OF THEMSELVES WHILST ENJOYING THEIR
                  RETIREMENT, PAYING ATTENTION TO THEIR HEALTH NEEDS AS WELL.



            Last Moments.




                  IN 2019, R.S’S HEALTH STARTED DETERIORATING GRADUALLY. ON THE EVENING
                  OF MARCH 15TH, 2021 IT BECAME NECESSARY TO TAKE HIM TO THE 37 MILITARY

                  HOSPITAL WHERE HE WAS IMMEDIATELY ADMITTED. AFTER TWO WEEKS, HIS CONDI-
                  TION  IMPROVED  QUITE  WELL  TO  THE  POINT  THAT  WE  WERE  ALL  HOPEFUL  HE
                  WOULD BE DISCHARGED FROM THE HOSPITAL ANY MOMENT THEREAFTER, BUT ONLY
                  TO BE MET WITH THE SAD NEWS OF HIS UNTIMELY DEMISE IN THE EARLY HOURS OF
                  MONDAY 29TH MARCH, 2021.




                                  R.S, EFO BUAMA SLEEP ON AND REST IN PEACE.
                             DZUDZOR, DZUDZOR , DZUDZOR LE NUTIFAFA ME AMEN.


                                                      Mr. R.S Owusu .                            9]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[PHOTO






                                                         GALLERY






       10.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Photo Gallery .












































































                          MEMORIES











                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.                            11]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Photo Gallery .
























































































              12                                  .]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Photo Gallery .














                                                  LOVE





























































                                                 MEMORIES











                                                        13             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Photo Gallery .


























































































                                                        14]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[R.S Owusu





             1943-2021

          “   You will always





              stay in our

              hearts.          “]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[LEGACY]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Legacy Gallery .

























































































                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.                          19]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[20. Tributes]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE BY WIFE TO THE
                                                  MEMORY OF R. S. K. B. OWUSU,

                                                  MY BELOVED HUSBAND.





                                                         Eternal lights flicker
                                                           In a distant sky.

                                                        Where have you gone;
                                                         Where is my friend,
                                                         I look to the heavens,
                                                    Hoping to see you once again
                                                        Where have you gone?
                              I'm searching for you, Buamamy beloved Husband, where have you gone?



                   Hmm! Death, man’s most venomous enemy, thought it could rob me of my joy and hope.
                   But no! it cannot, because the triumph of Christ’s resurrection reverberates in my heart.Thir-
                   ty-five years ago, I met a remarkable young man who was intelligent, knowledgeable,
                   confident, eloquent and charming. His name was Robinson Stephen Owusu. Buamaor
                   Kodzo as he was affectionately called became the love of my life and one of the best gifts
                   God gave me. It was the Lord who brought us together and He preserved our union till the
                   end.


                   We had our problems like every family but making up and resolving our issues was magi-
                   cal. It is often said there may be no perfect partner since perfection belongs to the almighty
                   God alone, but an ideal partner can be found in someone who has developed certain ways
                   that go beyond looks and success, and that was my Husband, my Kodzo, my Buama.

                   My trip down memory lane of thirty-five sweet years reminds me of how gentle, intelli-
                   gent and tactfully you approached every situation, this endeared you to me over the
                   years.


                   You were a supportive husband, a friend, an uncle, a father and a wise counsellor.

                   Buamawas a dedicated family man, He was the great oak tree which gave shade to his
                   large family both home and abroad. He duly earned the name Wofa Buama, due to how
                   he opened his arms wide, especially to his numerous nephews and nieces, much to the
                   admiration of many. As a big brother to your siblings, you always rose to the occasion and
                   showed leadership when it mattered most.

                   You were an honorable man and a stickler for discipline, especially with your time.You
                   would not compromise on matters of principle. Buama I am going to miss you so much,
                   now that you have left me, who is going to honk at me as a reminder that we are running
                   late? Who is going berate me for always being late? Who I’m I going have my petty
                   squabbles with?


                   Your condition which started as just a mere thing saw you getting admitted at 37 Military
                   hospital with much hope of a successful return home. Indeed, it was the first time you were
                   ever admitted at a hospital beyond a day ever since I met you over three decades ago. I
                   saw you undergo rigorous medical procedures and was encouraged by what seemed a
                   good recovery prognosis. I had huge hopes your recovery was just a matter of time.


                   21                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[The memories of those final days by your side at the hospital will forever remain etched
                   in my mind.  I still remember your firm and prolonged grips of my hand. Now it is clear
                   to me it was your way of saying goodbye and urging me to remain strong in your
                   absence.

                   That fateful day you passed on, started like one of the days I will prepare to come see you
                   at the hospital and do all that was required, with full hopes of your imminent recovery
                   and subsequent return home. I wish it would have been just a day the family and I could
                   shut the world out and have you to ourselves at home instead. A day when you would
                   have simply been Daddy and my husband. But now that day marks the beginning of a
                   painful and aching emptiness that we still cannot come to terms with.

                   How can Daddy be gone? How can he be forever silent? How can he not come walking
                   through the door of our home anymore? Are we never going to share our usual jokes any-
                   more?

                   Oh Buamawas that the best way of saying good bye? Was that the promise of a speedy
                   recovery you gave me? You have indeed left me with difficult questions only you can
                   answer.

                   In my despair, I lift up my eyes to the hills? where does my help come from? My help
                   comes from the Lord, the maker of heaven and earth.

                   Daddy, I will miss your voice. I will miss that well of wisdom and knowledge that I contin-
                   ually drew on. I will miss our drives to Have, church and other places, the jokes and stories
                   you told as we went, in a manner that only you could. We will miss the family times on
                   Sundays after church where Atta Kuma will tell his usual jokes and leave you in stitches
                   in front of the small gate, your favorite spot.


                   I will forever carry with me, the precious and many lovely memories of our journey
                   together, from our young days to that fateful Monday when you departed this earth.
                   As I ponder in grief over your sudden death I look back in time and it is dominated with
                   joyous memories of our over three decades long journey together. Thank you for all you did
                   to make the world a better place for us. We love you and miss you terribly.
                   Even though I am filled with grief and remain inconsolable for the huge void you have
                   left me with, I take consolation in the fact that you lived life to its fullest. I wish you noth-
                   ing but a perfect and peaceful rest in the bosom of the lord till we surely meet again on
                   the day of the resurrection.




                   Hede nyuie le nutifafa me...  Sleep easy my love…














                   22                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE FROM MATILDA





                   An honorable gentleman
                   Our dad was a man who lived his life based on set principles.
                   He believed in transparency and accountability. He taught us to be honest in our every
                   day dealings with people. He would always employ us to tell the truth and suffer the
                   consequences rather than lie because he said once you lie to someone about something and
                   they find out the truth they would never truly trust you again. This is a principle that we
                   have applied to our lives and teach our children to follow.
                   What we're feeling is so heavy on our hearts so much so that we can’t even put it into
                   words. We never thought of today like this. We saw it so far away and because of that
                   we never prepared ourselves for loosing you daddy.
                   We're wrestling a lot in our hearts but we pray that the good lord will grant us the grace
                   to eventually accept the fact that you are gone.
                   We've known you as a father and as a friend and we are grateful to have had you as a
                   parent.

                   We thank you for the discipline you instilled in us.
                   You lived your life With reference to 1timothy 6:12 and truly you have fought the good
                   fight with all your might. May God give you the crown of your good works and keep you
                   in His bosom till we meet again one day. You were an honorable man.
                   Daddy, babaa nawo. Rest in perfect peace.




                                       TRIBUTE FROM DORYCE




                   n honorable gentleman
                   My dad was a man who lived his life based on set principles.
                   He believed in transparency and accountability. He thought us to be honest in our every
                   day dealings with people. He would always employ us to tell the truth and suffer the
                   consequences rather than lie because he said once you lie to someone about something and
                   they find out the truth they would never truly trust you again. This is a principle that I
                   have applied to my life and teach my children to follow.
                   What I’m feeling is so heavy on my heart so much so that I can’t even put it into words. I
                   never thought of today like this. I saw it so far away and because of that I never prepared
                   myself for loosing you daddy.
                   I’m wrestling a lot in my heart but I pray that the good lord will grant me the grace to
                   eventually accept the fact that you are gone.
                   I’ve known you as a father and as a friend and I am grateful to have had you as a parent.
                   I thank you for the discipline you instilled in us.
                   You lived your life With reference to 1timothy 6:12 and truly you have fought the good
                   fight with all your might. May God give you the crown of your good works and keep you
                   in His bosom till we meet again one day. You were an honorable man.
                   Daddy, babaa nawo. Rest in perfect peace.




                   23                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[SEFA’S TRIBUTE TO DADDY






                                                    In ecc.3:1-2 says`

                                               to every thing there is season,
                                            and a time to every purpose under
                                          heaven.a time to be born , and a time
                                                                                          to   die …………’’


                   We called you Daddy, because that was who you truly were. You were not only a father
                   to your biological children but then to everyone you came into contact with both young
                   and old. Your sense of care and compassion was second to none and can be easily felt by
                   all of us, even by people who encountered you.

                   Death has actually robbed us  of a great treasure, death a necessity it will come when it
                   will come, we know one day but certainly not this time or this year as it did happened.
                   My last moment with Daddy was on the 27TH March 2021, it was Saturday late after-
                   noon l could vividly recall immediately l entered the ward and Daddy saw me he called
                   my name Sefa... but l did not understand , little did l know you were saying good bye.
                   Daddy was not bed ridden with little aide he walked and able to eat as well. Even your
                   short admission at 37 Military Hospital you were full life   wisdom. Later, Matilda, Auntie
                   Mawuse and her husband Mr. Obeng and also Eben Kay came almost simultaneously.
                   We  had  a  smooth  communication  with  Daddy  amidst  laughter.  Daddy  seems  to  be
                   fine, only dose off occasionally l believe because of the medication he was on. There was
                   no cause for alarm his condition was stable. We even prayed together with Daddy before
                   leaving the Hospital. Little did l suspect that was the last time l will ever see you again on
                   earth. I called mum when she was at the Hospital on Sunday 28TH March 2021, l asked
                   how Daddy was doing and that l was coming over .But mum said Daddy was fine so there
                   was no need for me come that day, l should rather make it on the weekend. l was shock
                   to  the  bone  when  l  called  mum  on  Monday  morning  29TH  March  2021,  then
                   Atta Kuma picked the call then l heard a loud cry at the background, he told me Daddy
                   passed on this morning and that l should come to the house immediately. l wept in my
                   office, sort  permission headed  towards Awoshie to verify for myself  and  the evidence
                   was clear on the ground.

                   Furthermore, l fully came to leave with Daddy in 1992, after ‘O’ Level, having  stayed
                   with my auntie for six years. l only left Daddy when l got married in 2015 December by
                   the grace God and moved out  in January 2016 to be on my own. We were a large family
                   by then, Daddy, Mum, Eben Kay, Matilda, Doris, Eddie, Mawuli, Regina, Setor  and
                   myself, Kennedy joined us later on. Doris was by then in university so she is hardly at
                   home. Also when we moved to Awoshie there was no light and water in the area only
                   one or two neighbours,the whole place was bush. Initially we used generator set before
                   Daddy connected light and water from Gbawe.Before then Daddy did underground reser-
                   voir for water storage this help us very much and even sold water to our  neighbours. ln
                   those days, l can vividly recall or remember  l used box iron to press Daddy’s cloths for the
                   week.



                   24                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Because there was no light when Mawuli have to iron for Daddy he will send the cloth all
                   the way to Auntie Mawuse’s house at Dansoman to press and he hardly stays at Awoshie.
                   Sometimes Eben Kay would ask Mawuli why he has to send the cloths that far and not
                   press the cloths at home by using the box iron. l have a lot of sweet memory to share,
                   before Daddy retired from Scanship ,every Christmas he bought crates of minerals for the
                   home which we enjoy a lot .l have another fond memory about Daddy was when l took
                   his car in absence and smashed ,he could have sacked me from the house but he did not.
                   This is clearly his demonstration of love towards me. However, there were some few things
                   he queried me about like coming home very late in the night and also one day he said to
                   me `you make your mother  worried about you when you go out and you don’t come back
                   and you do not also inform her’. Haven’t  stayed  with Daddy for over twenty years l will
                   say am grateful and thankful.

                   In conclusion, l thank God for given us such a great gift like Daddy, l know Daddy was a
                   good man, he love us took care and fed us as well. Although he had his own fault as any
 We called you Daddy, because that was who you truly were. You were not only a father   other human being.
 to your biological children but then to everyone you came into contact with both young
 and old. Your sense of care and compassion was second to none and can be easily felt by   Daddy you will always be in our mind
 all of us, even by people who encountered you.   Daddy, thank you
                   Daddy, we love you
 Death has actually robbed us  of a great treasure, death a necessity it will come when it                                           Daddy,fare thee well
 will come, we know one day but certainly not this time or this year as it did happened.
 My last moment with Daddy was on the 27TH March 2021, it was Saturday late after-
 noon l could vividly recall immediately l entered the ward and Daddy saw me he called   TRIBUTE FROM YASMINE
 my name Sefa... but l did not understand , little did l know you were saying good bye.
 Daddy was not bed ridden with little aide he walked and able to eat as well. Even your
 short admission at 37 Military Hospital you were full life   wisdom. Later, Matilda, Auntie
 Mawuse and her husband Mr. Obeng and also Eben Kay came almost simultaneously.   I was so excited when mum confirmed we were coming to see you in March grandpa  I
 We  had  a  smooth  communication  with  Daddy  amidst  laughter.  Daddy  seems  to  be                                          was also looking forward to eat Waakye with you in the mornings like we used to. But it
 fine, only dose off occasionally l believe because of the medication he was on. There was   wasn’t to be. God called you home before we got to Ghana but I am comforted by the fact
 no cause for alarm his condition was stable. We even prayed together with Daddy before   that at least I got to spend some time with you. I know that you are in heaven sitting by
 leaving the Hospital. Little did l suspect that was the last time l will ever see you again on   God’s righteous right hand. There’s no doubt in my mind that you will continue to guide
 earth. I called mum when she was at the Hospital on Sunday 28TH March 2021, l asked   the family from heaven and speak on our behalf. Your presence will continue to fill our
 how Daddy was doing and that l was coming over .But mum said Daddy was fine so there   lives until we meet again one day.
 was no need for me come that day, l should rather make it on the weekend. l was shock
 to  the  bone  when  l  called  mum  on  Monday  morning  29TH  March  2021,  then                         Grandpa, you will be missed dearly. Rest eternally in the bosom of The Almighty.
 Atta Kuma picked the call then l heard a loud cry at the background, he told me Daddy
 passed on this morning and that l should come to the house immediately. l wept in my
 office, sort  permission headed  towards Awoshie to verify for myself  and  the evidence
 was clear on the ground.    TRIBUTE FROM GRAND CHILDREN

 Furthermore, l fully came to leave with Daddy in 1992, after ‘O’ Level, having  stayed
 with my auntie for six years. l only left Daddy when l got married in 2015 December by
 the grace God and moved out  in January 2016 to be on my own. We were a large family   Little did we know that morning that God was going to call your name.
 by then, Daddy, Mum, Eben Kay, Matilda, Doris, Eddie, Mawuli, Regina, Setor  and   The Poet Rob Tranmer best speaks for us in his Broken Chain poem when he said, ‘’In life
 myself, Kennedy joined us later on. Doris was by then in university so she is hardly at   we loved you dearly, in death we do same. It broke our hearts to lose you, you did not go
 home. Also when we moved to Awoshie there was no light and water in the area only   alone; for part of us went with you, the day God called you home. You left us peaceful
 one or two neighbours,the whole place was bush. Initially we used generator set before   memories, your love is still our guide; and though we cannot see you, you are always at
 Daddy connected light and water from Gbawe.Before then Daddy did underground reser-  our side. Our family chain is broken, and nothing seems the same; but as God calls us one
 voir for water storage this help us very much and even sold water to our  neighbours. ln   by one, the chain will link again.’’
 those days, l can vividly recall or remember  l used box iron to press Daddy’s cloths for the
 week.             We will miss you dearly Grandpa.
                   Dzudz) le Nutifafa me.

                   25                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE FROM SISTER – MRS. IRENE DOH






                   "EMEVORVI" as I usually called you and  your response was "Sister".I Miss  our normal
                   weekly calls. I never expected you to leave the scene  so soon.I thank you for being there
                   for me in hard times and good times. Your Leadership in the family was great,your
                   absence will be felt for a long time.May you have a peaceful rest with the LORD.









                      TRIBUTE FROM ADOLF BUAMATSE OWUSU





                   I have fought the good fight, I have finished the race, I have kept faith.
                   Now there is in store for the crown of righteousness, which the Lord the righteous Judge,
                   will award to me on that day and not only to me, but also to all who have longed for his
                   appearing.
                   2 Timothy 4:7-8 New International Version

                   I heard the news of your demise the day I was discharged from hospital after a week in
                   operation. The news was like being hit with a sledge hammer. How could Efo Buama
                   leave us like that as though for the second time being left yet orphans again

                   We were very young when we lost our dear mom. I remember that in our young years
                   of grieve you called us aside and made a promise to us that for as long as you lived you
                   would look after us, a promise that would live with me all these years until your last
                   breathe. We thank you for this.

                   One story which I was told and was stuck with me is how I got my name "Buamatse". The
                   story goes that after the birth of my brother Stephen "aka Buama" he was expecting a boy
                   next. How disappointing was it to him when my sister Rebecca decided to emerge next. So
                   Buama was never going to give up on his prayers. Then, lo and behold it was finally my
                   turn, Buama's prayers has been answered and he named me Buamatse meaning Buama
                   Junior to satisfy Buama.


                   Efo, as we all grew to refer to him was like a column in the family, will be be difficult to
                   replace. We have lost a grate pillar of our time.


                   You have fought a good fight, you have finished the race.
                   Efo rest in eternal peace till we meet again







                   26                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE FROM SEWORNU OWUSU TO MY

                        BELOVED SENIOR BROTHER ROBINSON

                                     KODZO STEPHEN OWUSU.



                   Death The Leveller


                                            ‘The glories of our blood and state
                                         Are of shadows, not substantial things;
                                            There is no armour against Fate;
                                            Death lays his icy hands on kings;
                                                   Sceptre and Crown
                                                   Must tumble down
                                             And in the dust be equal made
                                        With the poor crooked scythe and spade
                                                                                      By James Shirley





                   The call came through to me that early Monday morning which is not normal, to
                   announce your passing away. I had a troubled night before.  The last time I spoke to you
                   about on Friday 26th of March, you said you were in the hands of the Lord. Even with
                   that strong faith, I sensed in my spirit that all was not well.

                   Efo, your passing is painful and full of void to me. You had taken on an enormous responsi-
                   bility immediately our mum had passed on at a tender age.  I remember you verbally
                   assured us of your unflinching responsibility to look after us. And truly to your words, you
                   quickly established yourself
                   In Accra with a secure job and brought us under your wings. You inspired me and found
                   me a job in your company ( Scanship/Travel Gh Ltd) but not on a silver platter. I seized
                   the opportunity to use the facilities and the office equipments to enhance my progress
                   which was recognized by management and I got promoted. You also opened my eyes to
                   have the opportunity of working among a conglomerate of Europeans, which had brought
                   about lot of change in my life.

                   You had also ensured that you provided me with accommodation in cream areas in Accra
                   ie Osu RE, Labone , Nyaniba and the South Labadi Estates for which I thank you very
                   much.


                   Efo, I was so proud of you when you had your next promotion as assistant accountant
                   before I left you to Nigeria.  You were very endeared to the management of Scan-
                   ship/Travel Gh Ltd so much so that you were always sought after. Because of the exposure
                   you gave me, my adventure in Nigeria was great in the job front.


                   Once again, when I relocated to the United Kingdom, what a fun it became as you were
                   visiting us consistently for about 8 yrs. Accompanying you to visit and present yourself to
                   your principals at London Putney was exciting.



                   27                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[I could not wait to visit you in Ghana to have quality time with you whenever the oppor-
                   tunity arose.  Alas covid-19 deprived me of seeing you for the last time. It hurt.

                   You never seek for trouble or be troubled. Your demeanour was always to be calm. You
                   advised me that to say sorry never demean you but rather raise one’s integrity.


                   Efo, you had lived a life of peace.  Your anger was always controlled or suppressed. You
                   never sowed division but aspired for unity and togetherness. Anybody who showed
                   respect to you, you reciprocated the same and you loved all.

                   Efo, you have done your best in life and the Lord call you to come Home and rest.  We
                   will miss you dearly as the vacuum your departure created cannot be filled.

                   May you rest peacefully in His bosom until we meet again.


                   Amen.





                              TRIBUTE FROM MARGARET GELI

                                             (SISTER INLAW)





                 Efo was someone I can never finish talking about. When I met my husband, he was the
                 one I leaned on because my husband had traveled overseas. Efo did everything for me. He
                 led in asking for my hand in marriage. He helped me do my paperwork so I could join my
                 husband. On the day, I left the country, Efo was the one who took me to the airport. Efo,
                 Efo, you fought a good a fight. You did a very good work here on earth. Not many in Efo’s
                 position, would have done that for me. Why have you left us so suddenly?  You were so
                 gentle and calm. I am yet to meet someone as peaceful as you. You had a listening ear and
                 were very accommodating. He gave the best advice and knew just what to say to calm
                 you in every situation you will find yourself. My husband till today, remembers the com-
                 forting words of Efo to him when they lost their mom. Those words come to mind whenev-
                 er they are gathered as a family. My husband will begin to cry and I will cry with him.
                 Sometimes I get fed up and ask him if he is the first to ever lose a mom then come back to
                 console him. My husband weeps whenever he remembers all his brother has done for him
                 even when Efo was alive. I admired Efo so much as a family elder that he was. Efo, you
                 can never be forgotten. The vacuum you have left can never be filled. When I heard he
                 was ill and had been admitted, I called him and said, ‘’Efo, you are all we have left oh, so
                 we are praying earnestly for you to get better so you can spend more time with us.’’ Little
                 did I know that was going to be our last conversation. It keeps ringing in my mind. I will
                 forever cherish every moment we shared. May God see all the peace and love you show-
                 ered here on earth and give you a perfect resting place. We love you but God loves you
                 more.
                 May He keep you in His abode till we meet again.






                   28                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[TRIBUTES BY NIECES & NEPHEWS

                                        ONLY REMEMBERED




                                        Fading away like the stars in the morning,
                                           Losing their light in the glorious sun.
                                    Thus would we pass from this earth and its toiling,
                                        Only remembered for what we have done.


                                          Only remembered, only remembered,
                                        Only remembered for what we have done.
                                    Thus would we pass from this earth and its toiling,
                                        Only remembered for what we have done.


                                         Only the truth that in life we have spoken,
                                          Only the seed that in life we have sown.
                                     These shall pass onwards when we are forgotten,
                                        Only remembered for what we have done.


                                     Who’ll sing the anthem and who’ll tell the story?
                                        Will the line hold, will it scatter and run?
                                           Shall we at last be united in glory?
                                        Only remembered for what we have done.

                                                                                                  By:
                                                        Horatius Bonar of Edinbugh, Scotland


                 Oh yes, we shall Remember you, as an uncle like no other. Yes, that is what you were. It
                 is difficult to compare you to any other, for you stood so tall, a colossus in the family; a
                 pillar so strong, a dependable shield; an oasis for the distressed lot in our generation.


                 You touched the lives of many of us in significant and subtle ways.  Your generosity was
                 legendary and your humility inexplicable. You availed yourself to all who sought your
                 counsel and support. Many of us did not call you “wofa”! For in the world of the Owusu
                 family, titles don’t matter! Everybody, young and old is referred to as “Hello”! We all grow
                 up into this culture of simplicity albeit within a context of respect for our family values.
                 You were one of those who helped build this culture of respectful informality in the family.

                 You were so gentle with us in matters of discipline. Your cool disposition and tolerance
                 dispelled our fears of being hauled before you to answer questions of misbehavior. Indeed,
                 we sometimes took your humility and gentleness so much for granted; we were so naive
                 to take these admirable virtues in you to be your weakness! However, time and circum-
                 stances have proven that in all situations you were strict, firm and resolute in your
                 decisions.


                 It is not going to be easy replacing you in the family. Your role as a unifier, the peace
                 maker, a friend, a servant uncle, a quiet listener, a just uncle, a resourceful and dependable
                 uncle, a trail blazer et al, will be missed greatly!



                   29                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[As you journey to the other world, look kindly upon us your surviving nephews and nieces.
                   Intercede for us from heaven that it may be well with us, as was always your wish for us.

                   You were not of many words, yet when you spoke your few words were laced with
                   wisdom that endures! You disliked too many complaints, especially those coming from our
                   parents to you! You believed in responsible family liberties and the need for some degree
                   of mistakes to be accommodated in our growing process. Thanks for your understanding. It
                   helped.

                   On a day like this, it’s difficult to say our goodbyes but we must! And so with great pain
                   and grief we say, adieu, the people’s uncle! Fare thee well, take your well-deserved rest,
                   “Hello”!


                   You will, indeed, be remembered! Rest In Peace and may your memory be a blessing to us!





                       Tribute to my Father-in-law by Kafui Senyeﬁa




                   Although distance was a barrier to my relationship with you, I enjoyed the little moments
                   we spent on the phone and the nuggets of wisdom you shared in shaping my ideology
                   about marriage and to ensure the longevity of my marriage to Mawuli.


                   I looked forward to meeting you again later this year and presenting to you, what would
                   have been your last grandbaby but alas, the Lord knew better and took you away.


                   Thanks for the quality of “love and life” you gave to my husband. I will always be remind-
                   ed of your sublime and calm nature which I admired from afar– I will miss your
                   WhatsApp status updates the most – I wake up to them on cold winter nights in Mary-
                   land and smile to myself – knowing that Mr. Owusu is awake and doing great.


                   I stand with the song writer in singing:


                                        Abide with me, fast falls the eventide
                                     The darkness deepens Lord, with me abide
                                      When other helpers fail and comforts flee
                                       Help of the helpless, oh, abide with me.


                                       Swift to its close ebbs out life's little day
                                     Earth's joys grow dim, its glories pass away
                                       Change and decay in all around I see
                                      O Thou who changest not, abide with me.


                                     Hold Thou Thy cross before my closing eyes
                                 Shine through the gloom and point me to the skies
                              Heaven's morning breaks, and earth's vain shadows flee
                                       In life, in death, o Lord, abide with me
                                           Abide with me, abide with me.


                   30                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Rest well Mr. Owusu as I affectionately called you, until we meet again at the pearly
                   gates of heaven – I pray the angels carry you on their wings into eternity.

                   Hede Nyuie – Hede le Nutifafa me.








                                   TRIBUTE FROM SON-IN-LAW






                   Tribute for a dear father-law ;  Mr. R.S Owusu.

                   When I came to ask the hand of my wife Matilda in marriage, little did I know my
                   father-in-law to be, was going to give me a pet name. He called me KU MAKU . Accord-
                   ing to my wife , he coined the name after a little encounter I had with him with some
                   contents in a bottle. He then went on and gave me a second name; AGBELI. To him AGBE-
                   LIKOR. I was looking forward to protest this recent name he has given me , till I heard the
                   bad news.

                   A great tree has fallen not just within the Owusu family, but also in the entire commu-
                   nity. You will be, forever missed.

                   Rest well in perfect peace.







                    TRIBUTE BY THE EVANGELICAL PRESBYTERIAN

                     CHURCH, NEW ABOSSEY OKAI, MATAHEKO IN

                     MEMORY OF THE LATE ROBINSON STEPHEN
                                                       OWUSU




                     “When the doors to the street are closed and the sound of grinding fades; when men rise-up
                     at the sound of birds, but all their songs grow faint. When men are afraid of heights and of
                     dangers in the street. When the almond tree blossoms and the grasshopper drags himself
                     along and desire no longer is, stirred. Then man goes to his eternal home, and mourners go
                     about the streets. Remember him-before the silver cord is severed, or the golden bowl is
                     broken, before the pitcher is shattered at the spring or the wheel broken at the well, and the
                     dust return to the ground it came from, the spirit returns to God who gave it.”
                     “Meaningless! Meaningless!” says the Teacher” “Everything is meaningless!!!” Eccl. 12:4-8








                   31                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[The late Robinson Stephen Owusu joined the E. P. Church, New Abossey Okai on 9th
                   March 1989 and joined the Men’s Fellowship later. Stephen was very active in church
                   activities. After years of dedicated service, he was nominated and consecrated as a Presby-
                   ter on 17th April 2005. Stephen Owusu was kind and gave advice especially on account-
                   ing issues to people who needed clarification on one monetary issue or the other in the
                   church. No wonder he was elected the Treasurer and Financial Secretary of the Welfare
                   Committee of the church.  He was a principled man who faithfully carried out his responsi-
                   bilities diligently to the admiration of congregants. His gentle and pleasant disposition
                   endeared him to many members of the church. As a member of the church session Stephen
                   normally provided cogent and intelligent arguments when financial issues were raised to
                   support his case. In some instances, he provided facts and figures to back his point.
                   Congregants of E. P. Church, New Abossey Okai got to know of his ill health and subse-
                   quent hospitalization at the 37 Military Hospital. Some members visited and prayed with
                   him at the hospital with the hope that he would get well soon. Unfortunately, news
                   reached us on Monday, 29th March 2021 that Stephen had passed on. The news of his
                   passing away was with great dismay, a big blow and pain to the church members. We
                   felt it was untimely and too sudden for death to lay its icy hands on him. Stephen, our
                   hearts are saddened by your physical absence amongst us. However, we take consolation
                   in the fact that you have joined the army of angels above.
                   The Leadership and members of the entire church say: fare thee well. May God grant you
                   perfect and everlasting peace in His bosom.
                   Dzudze le ŋutifafa me
                   AMEN!!!
                   FEAR NOT! I LIVE
                   MAGAVO O! MELE AGBE!
                   NEW ABOSS, EVER GREEN!
                   GREEN, GREEN, GREEN………
                   Dzudzo le ŋutifafa me.
                   AMEN!



                   The sudden death of Robinson Stephen Owusu shocked the entire E.P. Church New
                   Abossey Okai and Lartebiokorshie District




















                   32                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE BY E. P. CHURCH, NEW ABOSSEY OKAI,

                                          MEN’S FELLOWSHIP








                                            Now the labourer's task is o'er;
                                              Now the battle day is past;
                                              Now upon the farther shore
                                              Lands the voyager at last.
                                           Father, in thy gracious keeping,
                                     Leave we now thy servant sleeping. A-men.


                                                                                    (John Ellerton)
                                                                                         (MH: 976:1)







                   It is with much gratitude to the Almighty God that we, the members of E. P. Church New
                   Abossey Okai Men’s Fellowship have assembled here to bid farewell to one of our strong
                   Pillars in the Fellowship.
                   The late Robinson Stephen Owusu was a committed and dedicated member of the New
                   Abossey Okai Men’s Fellowship. His attendance at church and Men’s Fellowship
                   programmes was superb. He was a well-trained Accountant who worked in reputable
                   Organization. He brought his rich Accounting experience to the church and performed
                   creditably to the admiration of all. We consulted him on many financial issues of the
                   church, and he was ever ready to offer his knowledge and experience and to find a way
                   through whatever problem we were confronted with.
                   News reached the members of the Fellowship about Stephens hospitalization at the 37
                   Military Hospital. We arranged and paid him a visit, prayed with him for his speedy
                   recovery but alas, Stephen slipped peacefully away during the early hours of Monday,
                   29th March 2021. What a shock!!!
                   Who shall we turn to for those nourishing pieces of advice? We may no longer see you
                   but our memories of you will stay with us. You will always and forever have a special
                   place in our hearts. Bye, bye, Stephen.
                   May the Good Lord grant you Perfect Peace.
                   IN CHRIST!!! WE LIVE!!!
                   AMEN











                   33                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[TRIBUTE BY THE LOCAL PRESBYTERS’ UNION
                   EVANGELICAL PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH, NEW

                                   ABOSSEY OKAI, MATAHEKO






                   Those we love must some day pass beyond our present sight. They must leave us
                   and the world we know without their radiant light. But we know that like a
                   candle, their lovely light will shine to brighten up another place more perfect….
                   More divine. And in the realm of heaven where they shine so warm and
                   bright our loved ones live forevermore in God’s eternal light.

                                                                               (all.greatquotes.com)


                   Death is an inevitable end of man. It comes in its own time and no one can stop it from
                   coming. The timing is what makes it hard to bear. It was with utter shock that we received
                   the news our colleague’s passing in the morning of Monday, 29th March 2021. Neverthe-
                   less, we had to accept the reality that we are never in control of our lives.

                   Robinson Stephen Owusu was a gentleman who put more into the church than he took
                   out. Simply put, he never defaulted in paying his tithe as well as all the relevant and
                   approved dues by the church. To those who knew him well, he was a perfect gentleman.
                   Based on this exemplary and other Christian qualities, he was nominated and was among
                   nine Presbyters (four males and five females) consecrated on April 17, 2005.  Stephen was
                   full of wisdom. He was fair and firm especially with financial issues in the church. His
                   election as the Treasurer and Financial Secretary of the Welfare Committee of the church
                   and the Local Presbyters Union came as no surprise to the church members. Those who had
                   the good fortune of spending time with Stephen can attest to his peaceful demeanour and
                   his good sense of humour.

                   When news reached us that the Late Presbyter Robinson Stephen Owusu was unwell and
                   hospitalized at the 37 Military hospital, some Presbyters visited and prayed with him for
                   a speedy recovery. Little did we know that his journey on planet, earth, will end soon. It
                   was such a great shock when we learnt about the sudden death of our brother and
                   colleague. His death is a big blow to us which we find difficult to believe. A great tree has
                   fallen; another corner stone of the family of E. P. Church, New Abossey Okai Presbyters is
                   gone forever. A great vacuum has been created. We are grateful to the Lord Almighty for
                   the special gift you were to us and place on record our gratitude for all you did We shall
                   forever treasure you in our hearts and mind. In view of this, we all say Akpe!!!
                   Stephen, we love you, but God loves you most. May your creator give you rest.


                   Hadowola, Dzudzo le ŋutifafa me.
                   Di Yesu!!! Tututu!!!
                   AMEN!!!






                   34                                                             Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[HYMNS                                                                             35






               AND





               READINGS.








                                                  HYMN 589.






                                                                       TUTU WÒ AƉATSI,                   “

                                                                          GAFA KONYI O!

                                                                   NU SI DIM NÈLE LA,                1

                                                                           YESU ANA WÒ.

                                                                 NE ZÃ DO ƉE WÒ HÃ,


                                                                  NYE DZI, GBƆ ƉE ME!

                                                                   XƆ YESU DZI SE KO,

                                                                         AFA 'KƆ NA WÒ.
             “








                       ENYA WÒ NUXAXA,

             2         ƉO ŊU ƉE ‘ŊU KO!                            NE LUƲƆ BUBU LI,                   “

                                                                   SI LE NU XAM LA,
                       ANA ŊU NYUIA-ƉE HÃ
                       NAKE NA WÒ TSÃ.                          GBLƆ NU SIWO KATÃ                 3


                       ƔE DZE NA WÒ XOXO                            YESU WƆ NA WÒ!
                       LE DZIŊGƆLI ME.                    NÀDO GBE ƉA KPAKPLII,

                       DO GBE ƉA VEVIE KO,                          NÀYƆ YESU ŊKƆ!


                       ‘KEM ANYO NA WÒ.                                 YESU ALƆ̃ AWƆ

                                                                  NUWO KATÃ NYUIE.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[LE NYE XAXAWO KATÃ ME,                        “

                                                                   LE NYE VEVEWO KATÃ ME,


                                                            DZI ƉOA ƑONYE, MENYAE BENA,                       1

                                                                      MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE.

                                                                      MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE,

                                                                      MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE,

                                                        MAWU LI KPLIM, NU KA TA MAVƆ̃?

                                                                      MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE.






       “








                 NUKPEKEAMEWO VAA DZINYE
       2         HEDOA ŊƆDZI NA NYE LUƲƆ;

                 DZI ƉOA ƑONYE, MENYAE BENA,

                 MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE.                                                                            HYMN 337.

                 MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE...









                           LE DZƆGBENYUI KPLE VƆ̃ SIAA ME,                           “

                                NE NUWO NYO ALO GBLẼ NAM,

                               DZI ƉOA ƑONYE, MENYAE BENA,                        3

                                          MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE.

                                        MAWU ƉOA ŊKU DZINYE...






                                                                                                          36




                          Hymns and Readings.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[“





                NYE XƆXƆ ƑE KPE GBADZAA,


         1      SITSOƑE MAVƆ, ƔLAM DZRO!

                NA WÒ ƲU KƆKƆE NAKLƆ
                NYE NU VƆ̃WO KATÃ ƉA;


                EYA NYE NYE XƆXƆ, SI

                ƉEM TSO NU VƆ̃ SI ME KEŊ.















                                                                     NYE DƆWƆWƆ ƉE SIA ƉE                         “
                                                                      MADZE WÒ SE LA ŊU O;                    2

                                                              NE MEDZ’A-GBAGBA ƲUU HÃ,
           HYMN 318.    3        ESI MEDA ‘HE ŊUTI,                 NEGBE WÒ LƆLƆ̃ LA KO.T
                        “
                                                                       NE MEFA ‘VI GƆ̃ HÃ LA,

                                                                      MAƉE NYE NU VƆ̃ ƉA O,





                                 MEVA WÒ ‘TITSOGA GBƆ;

                                 MEƑO ƉI, KLƆ ŊUTINYE!

                                 MEGBƆDZƆ, O, XƆ NAM DZRO!

                                 NE MÈKLƆ ŊUTINYE O,

                                 EKEMA ƉE KO MAKU.

                                                                            AZƆ NE MELE AGBE                      “
                                                                          ALO NE MEVA KU LA,


                                                                          NE VIVITI GƆ̃ DO ƉEM                4

                                                                    NE MEDO ƉE ŊKUWÒ ME,

                                                                  NYE XƆXƆ ƑE KPE GBADZA,

                                                               NA MAƔLA ƉE GBƆWÒ DZRO!
    37




                                          Hymns and Readings .]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[“

                    Hymn 651.                                                    Hymn 298.





                O YESU, LÉM Ɖ’A-SI NYUIE                                 SITSOƑE NA LUƲƆ GBƆDZƆ,                       “
                                                                                     NE VEVESESE HO,
         1      NE NÀKPLƆM YI,                                            EYE FUƉEƉEWO NYRA HÃ,                     1


                SE ƉE MADZO L’A-FI SIA
                YI MAVƆ ME!                                                 MELE MƆ KPƆM NA WÒ.


                NYE ƉEƉE NYEMATEA ŊU
                Ɖ’A-FƆ HÃ O;                                        MEGBLƆ LE FU SIA FU ME BE,

                AFI SI WÒA NÀYI LA,                                            WÒ KOE NYE DƆYƆLA,                      “
        “
                NÀKPLƆM Ɖ’A-SI.                                                                                   2
                                                                            WÒ NYA LA ATE ŊU AFA

                                                                                  NYE VEVE KATÃ NU.

                NE WÒ AMENUVEVE

       2        YƆ NYE DZIME,                                            KE NE ƉIKEKE SƆ GBƆ LA,                       “


                LE DZIDZƆ KPLE FU SIAA ME
                MAGBƆ ƉE ME.                                                    MEGBƆDZƆ LE ŊUWÒ,


                VIWÒ BELI NADZUDZƆ                                                AKƆFAFA NU TSINA,               3
                L’A-KƆWÒ ME,                                                    MƆKPƆKPƆ HÃ BUNA.


                AMIA ‘ƑE ŊKUWO FAFƐ
        “
                LE XƆSE ME.
                                                                          MAWU VAVÃ, ‘FI KA MAYI?                      “


                                                                         WÒE NYE NYE MƆKPƆKPƆ;

                NE WÒ ŊUSẼ LA GALE                                      NYE LUƲƆ MEKPƆ SITSOƑE,                   4

       3        ƔAƔLA ƉEM HÃ,                                                  NEGBE LE GBƆWÒ KO!


                WÒ LA ÀKPLƆM TO ZÃ ME
                VA KELI ME.

                AZƆ LÉM Ɖ’A-SI SESIẼ,                                        AMENUVEVEMƆA ƲU ƉI,                       “

                NE NÀKPLƆM YI,                                                  NA DZUDZƆ LUƲƆNYE;


                SE ƉE MADZO L’A-FI SIA                                  MABƆBƆ ƉOKUINYE NA WÒ,                    5

                YI MAVƆ ME!                                                    AKPƆ MƆ WÒ AFƆ NU.


              38                          Hymns and Readings .]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[“
                                                                            Hymn 651.



                DƆ ‘LƆ̃, LƆLƆ̃TƆ, DƆ ‘LƆ̃ NÀDZUDZƆ,


         1      ZIƆ WÒ TA ƉE WÒ XƆLA Ƒ’A-KƆ NU;
                MÍELƆ̃ WÒ VEVIE, YESU LƆ̃ WÒ WU;

                DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!



                                                         ÈMLƆ ‘NYI ABE VIDZĨ DZAA ENE,                         “

                                                       KE MÀGANYƆ ƉE XEXE SIA ME O;                        2
        “       VA SE ƉE XEXE SIA NU AVA YI,                DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!
                                                         DZUDZƆ VIVI TRƆ ZU TƆWÒ AZƆ,









       3        WÒAƑO ‘ƑE KƆKƆETƆWO ƑU Ɖ’E-GBƆ;

                VA SE ƉE SI AGBE SIA AWU NU,

                DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!



                                                     VA SE ƉE TSITRETSIŊKEKEA NAƉO,                            “

                                                          AME SIWO DƆ ‘LƆ̃ LE YESU ME,
        “
                                                     WOATSI TRE LE ŊUTIKƆKƆE GÃ ME,                      4


                                                            DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!


                VA SE ƉE EƑE LƆLƆ̃ KƆKƆE LA

       5        AWƆ WÒ NÀKLẼ ABE ‘YA Ŋ’TƆ ‘NE,
                ‘YE WÒAƉƆ WÒ FIAKUKU LA NA WÒ,

                DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!


                                                      DƆ ‘GBE, LƆLƆ̃TƆ, MENYE HEDE O,                    6     “


                                                                ESUSƆ ƲE KO, ETƆ VEVIWO
        “       VA SE ƉE MÍAKPE ‘ƑE FIAZIKPUI ŊGƆ,
                                                     AVA NƆ HA KƆKƆE MA ME TEGBEE,

                                                            DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!






       7        ADO DZƆDZƆENYENYE Ƒ’A-WU ƔIWO                                                 39
                EYE MÍANƆ MÍA XƆLA GBƆ TEGBEE,


                DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE! DƆ ‘GBE!]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[“
         896. Now Praise We Great And Famous Men.






                     NOW PRAISE WE GREAT AND FAMOUS MEN,

              1      THE FATHERS NAMED IN STORY;


                     AND PRAISE THE LORD, WHO NOW AS THEN
                     REVEALS IN MAN HIS GLORY.



                                  PRAISE WE THE WISE AND BRAVE AND STRONG,                                     “


                                                      WHO GRACED THEIR GENERATION,
            “
                            WHO HELPED THE RIGHT, AND FOUGHT THE WRONG,                                    2

                                                        AND MADE OUR FOLK A NATION.



                     PRAISE WE THE GREAT OF HEART AND MIND,


            3        THE SINGERS SWEETLY GIFTED,

                     WHOSE MUSIC LIKE A MIGHTY WIND

                     THE SOULS OF MEN UPLIFTED.




                                          PRAISE WE THE PEACEFUL MEN OF SKILL,                                 “

                                                      WHO BUILDED HOMES OF BEAUTY,


            “
                                               AND, RICH IN ART, MADE RICHER STILL                       4
                                                             THE BROTHERHOOD OF DUTY.




                     PRAISE WE THE GLORIOUS NAMES WE KNOW,


            5        AND THEY WHOSE NAMES HAVE PERISHED,
                     LOST, IN THE HAZE OF LONG AGO,

                     IN SILENT LOVE BE CHERISHED.




                                                IN PEACE THEIR SACRED ASHES REST,                              “

                                                     FULFILLED THEIR DAYS ENDEAVOR;


                            THEY BLESSED THE EARTH, AND THEY ARE BLESSED                                 6

                                                             OF GOD AND MAN FOREVER.
                      40]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[thank you












                     We deeply appreciate and gratefully


           acknowladge your kind expression of sympthy.

                             It will always be remembered

























                                                      by the family of the late

                                                                   Mr. R.S Owusu.]]></page></pages></Search>